<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title>Project &#8220;a CQRS Journey&#8221;</title>
  <link href="http://cqrsjourney.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://cqrsjourney.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-05-01T11:04:47-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://cqrsjourney.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name>Microsoft patterns &amp; practices</name>
    
      <email>cqrsdv@live.com</email>
    
  </author>

  
  <entry>
    <title>Open Call for Enhancements to Event Store Implementation</title>
    <link href="http://cqrsjourney.github.com/blog/2012/05/01/Open-Call-For-Enhancements-To-Event-Store/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-01T10:36:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://cqrsjourney.github.com/blog/2012/05/01/Open-Call-For-Enhancements-To-Event-Store</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In the process of our conversion of the Registration process BC to use event sourcing, we have realized we needed some robust event sourcing infrastructure (both for storing the events, and publishing them). We wanted this implementation to be Windows Azure-friendly, as this is where we’ll bedeploying our system to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have now built our initial implementation of the Azure table-based event store and it’s ready for a broad community review and for enhancements. It seems to be self-contained enough and will benefit from crowd-sourcing. Get it from here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Repo: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mspnp/cqrs-journey-code&quot;&gt;https://github.com/mspnp/cqrs-journey-code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Infrastructure solution: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mspnp/cqrs-journey-code/blob/dev/source/Infrastructure.sln&quot;&gt;https://github.com/mspnp/cqrs-journey-code/blob/dev/source/Infrastructure.sln&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;We really look forward to your participation in getting this event store production ready!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Notes:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There’s another implementation based on SQL server. It is meant for running the sample app locally and it’s not ready for production. Nor is it in our scope to make it production-ready. So, when prioritizing where to direct your effort, please choose the Azure table-based implementation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is currently not intended to be a general-purpose, pluggable component. We’ve designed and developed it to fit with our sample application.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>The Road to V1</title>
    <link href="http://cqrsjourney.github.com/blog/2012/04/12/Road-to-V1/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-12T15:40:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://cqrsjourney.github.com/blog/2012/04/12/Road-to-V1</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Handling Complexity and Change&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;DDD and ES reduce complexity and cost of change. They would look like useless magic in stable and predictable projects.&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;em&gt;- Rinat Abdullin, CQRS Advisors Mail List&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the topics discussed on the CQRS Advisors Mail List was how to make the CQRS Journey Project more realistic. In the real world, projects face uncertainty, risk, and volatility in requirements. One of the benefits of applying ideas from DDD and using event sourcing is to make that uncertainty, risk, and volatility more manageable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of our CQRS Journey, we are planning a pseudo-production release of V1 of the Contoso Conference Management System that includes the core conference management functionality. We will then explore, and document our experiences of enhancing and maintaining the V1 release as we continue to work on the Conference Management System.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Contents of the V1 Release&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following sections outline our planned functionality for the V1 release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Conference Management&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will be a simple CRUD style bounded context that enables a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mspnp/cqrs-journey-wiki/wiki/Ubiquitous-language&quot;&gt;Business Customer&lt;/a&gt; to create and manage conferences. A Business Customer will be able to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create and update the conference data such as name, description, and dates.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Publish and un-publish a conference.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manage the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mspnp/cqrs-journey-wiki/wiki/Ubiquitous-language&quot;&gt;Seat Types&lt;/a&gt; (e.g. full-conference, workshop, cocktail party) available at a conference.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;View a list of &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mspnp/cqrs-journey-wiki/wiki/Ubiquitous-language&quot;&gt;Attendees&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h3&gt;Registrations&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This bounded context will implement the CQRS pattern and use event sourcing. The functionality in this bounded context includes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enabling a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mspnp/cqrs-journey-wiki/wiki/Ubiquitous-language&quot;&gt;Registrant&lt;/a&gt; to create an &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mspnp/cqrs-journey-wiki/wiki/Ubiquitous-language&quot;&gt;Order&lt;/a&gt; for seats at a conference.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Handling partial fulfillment of Orders.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enabling a Registrant to locate a previously created order using an &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mspnp/cqrs-journey-wiki/wiki/Ubiquitous-language&quot;&gt;Access Code&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enabling a Registrant to assign Attendees to Seats.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A task-based UI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h3&gt;Integration&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Conference Management and Registrations bounded contexts will be integrated so that any changes made by the Business Customer to the quota of Seats at a Conference are detected by the Registrations bounded context. Information about the Attendees is also shared between the two bounded contexts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Payments&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part of the Registration Process includes the Registrant making a payment for the Order. The system will include a fake payment service that simulates handling payments by credit card and by invoice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Infrastructure&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Contoso Conference Management System will be deployed to Windows Azure and use the Windows Azure Service Bus to provide its messaging infrastructure for Commands and Events. It will also be possible to run the application locally without requiring a Windows Azure subscription.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;More Information&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can follow our work in these two GitHub repositories:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mspnp/cqrs-journey-doc&quot;&gt;cqrs-journey-doc repository&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mspnp/cqrs-journey-code&quot;&gt;cqrs-journey-code repository&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;You can track our progress against the V1 release milestone:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mspnp/cqrs-journey-code/issues?milestone=4&quot;&gt;V1 Release Milestone&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Sample Application Overview</title>
    <link href="http://cqrsjourney.github.com/blog/2012/03/30/Sample-Application-Overview/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-30T10:15:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://cqrsjourney.github.com/blog/2012/03/30/Sample-Application-Overview</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Contoso Conference Management System&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post summarizes the key features and functionality of the proposed Contoso Conference Management System that we are builing in our CQRS Journey projects.
You can read our motivation for choosing this domain &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.msdn.com/b/agile/archive/2012/01/24/picking-a-domain-for-cqrs-journey-ri.aspx&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mspnp/cqrs-journey-doc/blob/master/Journey_00_Preface.markdown&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contoso plans to build an online conference management system that will enable Contoso&amp;#8217;s customers to plan and manage conferences that may be held at a physical location. The system will enable Contoso&amp;#8217;s customers to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plan the tracks, sessions, and speakers that make up a conference.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manage the calls for speakers and paper submission process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manage registration (the sale of seats) for the conference.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manage the conference on site, including badge printing and attendee lists.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The following sections describe these functions in more detail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Conference Management System will be a multi-tennant, cloud-hosted application. Business customers will need to register with the system before they can create and manage their conferences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Conference Planning&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When a business customer creates a new conference, he must first define some characteristics of the conference such as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will the paper submission process require reviewers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What will be the fee structure for paying Contoso.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assigning key personnel such as the Program Chair and the Event Planner.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;Building a Program&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The business customer must define the conference program. For a simple conference this may be defined directly. For a more complex conference this may involve several steps:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identifying Tracks and Track Chairs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identifying Reviewers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Making calls for submissions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reviewing the papers and assigning speakers to sessions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finalizing Track programs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;Selling Seats&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The business customer will define how many seats are available for the conference and also for any events that are part of the conference that only limited numbers may attend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The system must manage the sale of seats to ensure that the conference and sub-events are not over subscribed. This part of the system will also operate wait-lists so that if cancellations are made, then the seats can be re-allocated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The system will require that the names of the attendees are associated with the purchased seats so that badges can be printed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;On-site Management&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When attendees arrive at the conference they should be registered against an attendee list, given badges, and given the opportunity to purchase additional seats for any extra events they would like to attend. The system that runs on-site at the conference should not assume that it is permanently connected to the main conference management system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Additional Features&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contoso plans to roll out additional features as and when resources are available. These include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support for Event Planners to manage equipment, signage, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tracking attendees at sessions via a barcode on the badge.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Score submissions for session feedback.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Live feed of session scores to track the best sessions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reporting feeback to speakers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Archiving conference materials.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Publishing proceedings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;Ubiquitous language&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mspnp/cqrs-journey-wiki/wiki/Ubiquitous-language&quot;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; are the working definitions for the terms in our ubiquitous language for the Conference Managament System sample we are building. We will be adding to and modifying this list as the project proceeds&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;More info&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow our progress in these 2 repos (you can set the watchers):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mspnp/cqrs-journey-doc&quot;&gt;https://github.com/mspnp/cqrs-journey-doc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mspnp/cqrs-journey-code&quot;&gt;https://github.com/mspnp/cqrs-journey-code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Taking Community Contributions</title>
    <link href="http://cqrsjourney.github.com/blog/2012/02/25/Taking-Community-Contibutions/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-25T06:45:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://cqrsjourney.github.com/blog/2012/02/25/Taking-Community-Contibutions</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We have positioned the CQRS guidance project as a learning journey. We’ve formed a stellar &lt;a href=&quot;http://cqrsjourney.github.com/advisors/members/&quot;&gt;advisory board&lt;/a&gt; and performed some &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.surveymonkey.com/s/cqrsguide&quot;&gt;public consultation&lt;/a&gt; that helped us scope the project initially. While this is good news, we recognize that for this project to be successful, we need to be not only open and transparent, but we also need to collaborate with the community (in its way a global village) more closely. That’s why we are extremely happy and proud to announce that for the first time in the history of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://msdn.com/practices&quot;&gt;Microsoft patterns &amp;amp; practices&lt;/a&gt; team, the following: &lt;strong&gt;In the true spirit of open source, we will be taking community contributions on the CQRS Journey project&lt;/strong&gt;. This means:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The written guidance and the sample code will be developed in the open and with community involvement.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We, Microsoft patterns &amp;amp; practices team, will review and accept contributions that meet our guidelines.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The final deliverable will have an open source license (&lt;a href=&quot;http://opensource.org/licenses/Apache-2.0&quot;&gt;Apache 2.0&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The project will be hosted on GitHub. Our repositories are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Main code repo&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mspnp/cqrs-journey-code&quot;&gt;https://github.com/mspnp/cqrs-journey-code&lt;/a&gt;. Also, includes our prioritized backlog of work items (published under &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mspnp/cqrs-journey-code/issues&quot;&gt;Issues&lt;/a&gt;) and includes stories, dev and test tasks, and bugs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Guidance repo&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mspnp/cqrs-journey-doc&quot;&gt;https://github.com/mspnp/cqrs-journey-doc&lt;/a&gt;. Also, includes the backlog of doc stories, tasks, and content bugs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project wiki&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mspnp/cqrs-journey-wiki&quot;&gt;https://github.com/mspnp/cqrs-journey-wiki&lt;/a&gt;, where we will try to reconcile various key CQRS and ES related terms and also maintain the ubiquitous language for the domain of the sample application we are building.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;You can find the contributions guidelines under Contribute section.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, check out our company-wide &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.microsoft.com/en-us/openness/default.aspx#home/videos/Commitment-to-Openness&quot;&gt;openness initiative&lt;/a&gt; and brace yourself for a ride! We look forward to working with you! Please keep sending us your feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
